Episode 11 "Brother and Sister"
Aren't your parent-teacher meetings today?
Yeah.
Did you want to eat?
Yes, please. I wanted more time to sleep,
so I didn't eat on my way home.
If you go to bed now,
will you be up in time?
Well, I think so. Let's see...
Let me go over things one more time.
Yuta-kun, yours is at 4:20, right?
Yes.
And Saki... yours is 4:40?
Did I get that right?
That's right.
You really won't get much sleep, then.
I'll be fine as long as I'm up by 2:00.
The only problem is that no one
will be home around that time.
If you want, I can give you a call.
Oh, thank you, Taichi-san!
Mom, Dad has work, too. Don't impose on him.
It's fine! It's no big deal.
Then I'm counting on you
for a very harsh wake-up call!
Sure.
Hey, what are you up to?
Nothing. Just killing time.
My meeting is today.
Ah, you too, huh? What time?
4:20.
Oh, ours are close. Mine's at 4:00.
But if it's that late,
you could've gone home first, right?
I know Saki did.
Huh?
I have to go home because I forgot something.
I'll go ahead
and wake Mom up,
and wake Mom up, so don't worry about that.
Thank you!
Thank you! Appreciate it!
Hey, are you even listening?
Oh, er, sorry. What?
I was just saying... you're into Saki, aren't you?
No, I'm not.
Is that the truth?
You know that Ayase-san and I are siblings.
You still call her "Ayase-san" even now.
But you're only stepsiblings, right?
And that practically just happened,
so aren't you basically like strangers?
I'm telling you it's not like that.
It's not, huh?
Then is it okay if I root for someone else?
Um...
If I know another guy likes Saki,
is it okay if I try to set them up?
That's what I'm asking.
That's not really something you
should be asking my permission for.
It's not?
No.
So you two never ran into
each other at school before?
We probably did. I just don't remember it.
What a gentleman.
You don't ever stare at the pretty girls?
That wouldn't go over well these days.
Well, as long as you don't get any
funny ideas, I don't think they'd mind.
Can you really tell if someone's
got funny ideas?
Of course!
You sound so certain.
It's fine. If there's a misunderstanding,
you just have to apologize.
You've got thick skin.
This is it.
Thank you.
Yuta-kun,
I'll do my best, okay?
I appreciate it.
So, in summary,
if he keeps working this hard,
he shouldn't have any trouble getting
into a famous university in Tokyo.
Is that right?
I'm sure it's because you did
an excellent job bringing him up.
Uh...
Yes. I'm very grateful to my mother.
Mm-hmm.
Next, you just need to decide
where you'd like to apply.
You'll get my stamp of approval
wherever you want to go.
Thank you very much.
Ayase-san's classroom is this way.
I'd better hurry. Also, thank you
for what you said, Yuta-kun!
I'm so happy you see me as your mom!
Uh, please don't pull on my arm.
I'm getting all teary-eyed!
Oh, gosh...
Yuta-kun, what do you want for dinner?
Uh, well...
F-First, would you mind letting me go?
If I'm perfectly honest with you,
I was somewhat worried about
Saki-san during the first term.
There were some unpleasant rumors
circulating about her behavior.
However, I see things differently now.
I could tell by observing Saki-san that
she isn't anything like the rumors say.
I know there are other teachers who say
this or that about her appearance,
but I understand wanting
to dress up and look pretty.
I'll just say one thing.
Try to keep it within appropriate
bounds for a high school student.
I will.
Now, let's talk about your future plans.
Your problematic language arts grade
started to improve in the second term.
Have you thought about colleges
you'd like to apply to?
I'd like to find one with low tuition costs
that will put me in a good
position for the job market.
How about Tsukinomiya Women's College?
Tsukinomiya?
I've heard it's very prestigious.
I'm not sure I'm...
With your current performance,
I think you have a shot if you work hard.
It would definitely give you
a boost on the job market.
It's a public school, so tuition is low.
It might be exactly what you're looking for.
I'd never even considered it.
Why not go and see it?
Look. They even have an open
campus event this weekend.
Appropriate bounds, huh?
I think if you try to stay too appropriate,
you drive yourself nuts.
Huh? What?
Nothing.
So, what'll it be?
I'll go tomorrow.
I'll check out the open campus by myself.
I see.
Tsukinomiya, huh? I'm so thrilled that
both of my children are such good students!
Yuta-kun was told that he could
get into any school he wanted.
Oh.
And listen to this! Yuta-kun's
homeroom teacher actually said...
Reception
Saturday, September 26th
Yomiuri-san?
Wow! You came to visit
my college? I'm so happy!
If you'd told me, I would've welcomed you in!
It was a last-minute decision.
You came for the sample lecture, right?
Yeah, I did.
Good! There's still some time,
so let me show you all around.
Huh? But...
Don't be shy, don't be shy!
Uh...
What have we here, Yomiuri-kun? Is this
dazzling young lady a friend of yours?
Kudo-sensei?
Kudo-sensei is giving today's
sample lecture on ethics.
This is Ayase Saki.
She works at the bookstore with me.
Nice to meet you. I'm Kudo Eiha.
I can tell you're struggling
with something right now.
We've got some time, so would you
mind joining me in my office?
I may be able to give you
the answer you're looking for.
Always hitting on someone...
Get on up here.
To be honest, I've already heard
a bit about you from Yomiuri-kun.
About me?
Yes. More precisely, about the two of you.
You know?
Let me think... What was it she called him?
Do you mean Asamura-kun?
Ah, so his name's Asamura-kun.
You had no idea, did you?
Correct. I didn't know his name yet.
Surprisingly, Yomiuri-kun is actually
pretty careful with personal info.
Metaethics
Kudo Eiha
General Ethics
I'll cut to the chase. You've fallen
for Asamura-kun, haven't you?
However, according to
conventional ethical standards,
he's someone you shouldn't have feelings for.
What makes you say that?
Well, that's all the proof I needed.
I don't think I like you very much.
I do like honest girls, though.
So? I asked you a question.
Do you like Asamura-kun?
I think he's a good brother.
Not that kind of "like." I'm asking if
you have romantic feelings for him.
He's my brother.
But you're not related.
A stepbrother is still a brother.
Yet he's only been one for three short months.
I'm not really sure myself.
Asamura-san.
Going to lunch, Fujinami-san?
Yes, and...
since you came to sit near me,
I thought maybe you had something to say.
Oh, yeah, but it isn't really
anything important.
It isn't? Are you going anywhere for lunch?
I was thinking the convenience store.
Me, too. We can eat in the lounge.
Egg Salad
Sockeye
Salmon
Kelp
Spicy Cod Roe
And that's what changed for
you over these three months?
I think we have a misunderstanding.
What do you mean?
What if those aren't romantic feelings at all?
That can't be...
Hey, relax. Let's just think about this.
According to what Yomiuri-kun told me,
it sounds like your personal
style is to come off strong.
Yeah...
But for you, the way you dress
is performative, isn't it?
You use fashion as a way to show yourself off.
Your appearance is something
you've constructed very carefully.
However, though you're still a high schooler
on the inside, the fact that you came
to see a top college makes me think
you're much more serious than that.
It was recommended to me
at a parent-teacher meeting.
The persona you're showing off to the world
wouldn't come visit a school like this
just because a teacher told her to.
I'm not trying to act like some easy girl,
and I don't want people to think I'm one.
I just want to prove that I can use what
I have to look "cute" or "pretty" or whatever,
and for people to see that.
And I didn't come today
because I'm a serious student.
I just thought it might help me
make the best life I can for myself.
I'm trying to convince myself that it will.
That explains it.
Your seemingly contradictory
appearance and personality
are both things you've crafted intentionally.
But I'll also add this.
You're the kind of person who absolutely
doesn't want others seeing her weaknesses.
Listen, I can tell you're the type who's
always fighting. Always by yourself.
The stronger the fight,
the more you need love and approval.
So when shown the
tiniest gesture of support,
you immediately get attached.
I was actually going to turn you down.
Turn me down?
I was gonna say, "I come to
cram school to study, not for that."
So you thought I was hitting on you?
But it doesn't seem that way now.
As soon as we started eating,
the conversation hit a dead end.
Sorry. I don't go to school,
so people think I must be really easy.
You don't go to school?
Oh, sorry. You don't have to go into detail.
It's all right. To be clear,
I don't go to school during the day.
Oh, you go to night school?
If I say "night school," "female,"
and "hangs out in arcades at midnight,"
what kind of person would you imagine?
I'd just think she's a night school student
who goes to arcades late at night.
Would you really?
Yeah. Why?
You wouldn't hit on me because
you thought I was an easy lay?
Sorry. I don't know anyone else
who goes to night school,
so I don't have any preconceptions about that.
Huh.
I like that you're so unbiased.
Do you look at everything impartially?
Well, I think I make an effort to be.
I'd bet that you know very few people who
truly understand who you are deep down.
That's why, arbitrary as it was, you fell for
someone who suddenly appeared by your side.
No, that's...
Not what happened?
Can you say that with confidence?
You should try engaging
with a wider variety of people.
You might find someone else
you're drawn to one day,
and that may help you resolve
these issues without all the stress.
I should meet someone else?
I'm not telling you to go out and find a lover.
But a limited perspective is the
enemy of reason and intellect.
I think I can agree.
Good.
However...
If you connect with another
person you're attracted to
and your feelings remain unchanged,
then those are your true feelings,
and you should always treasure them.
All right.
There you go. It's also important
not to be so stubborn, Saki-chan.
Would you mind calling me Ayase?
Taboos in Ethics                coupled siblings               Ethics in Contemporary Society
culture, customs ->            children from different parents                                   values
change over time           ancient times                                           society ≠ individual
sneaking in                         Egypt, Greece, Persia, Japan                    revision of ethics
consanguineous marriage                  today
Will you be in the study
lounge again tomorrow?
I have afternoon classes on the weekend,
but in the morning, yeah.
Then we should eat lunch again.
I know a good, cheap restaurant.
Okay, thanks.
Um, you didn't see a rice ball you
wanted at the convenience store?
You were watching me?
Yeah...
Well, with rice balls, th-the seaweed
sticks to your teeth, right?
So I passed.
See you tomorrow.
Asamura
Ayase
Huh? And Yomiuri-senpai was there?
Yeah. She was working reception.
So she goes to a top women's college...
There was also a really weird professor there.
Weird?
I'm not sure how else to describe her.
We kinda got into an argument.
I was exhausted by the end of it.
But you had fun, right?
Oh, yeah, I did.
Are you thinking of going to Tsukinomiya now?
I think at college,
it all begins when you start to realize
how you think about things.
Like a place you go to work things out.
I do think I want to give it a shot now.
Yeah? That's great.
So what about you, Big Brother?
Will you keep going to that study lounge?
Well, I guess so.
I'm supposed to meet a friend from
cram school for lunch again tomorrow.
Oh, really?
That's great, Big Brother.
Mm-hmm.
She's right. This should
actually be a good thing.
Ayase-san met someone who
made her want to try college,
and I found a friend
I can talk to at cram school.
We're both making new connections.
This is how things should be.
We each have our own separate plans,
and our paths don't overlap.
Bit by bit, we're getting closer
and closer to becoming
a perfectly normal seventeen-year-old
brother and sister.
Episode 12 "
and
"